字幕翻譯製作: goodliuwu
哈里森·福特
銀翼殺手
魯特格爾·哈爾那個複製人頭目
肖恩·楊美女主角
配樂：范吉利斯
導演：雷德利·斯科特
21世紀初期，泰瑞爾公司發展機器人
演化至NEXUS連結階段——一種實質上與人類相同的存在
以複製人聞名
NEXUS 6 型複製人比起創造他們的基因工程師們
有更優越的力量及靈活度，以及起碼是同等的智慧
複製人在「地外世界」被當作奴工來使用
從事危險的探索，及對其他星球的殖民任務
NEXUS6型戰鬥隊在某個地外世界殖民地發動了一場血腥暴亂
此後，複製人在地球被宣佈為非法——違者處死
特種警察小隊——銀翼殺手部隊
奉命擊殺任何入侵的複製人
這不稱為處決
而稱為「除役」
洛杉磯 2019年11月
下一個對象，科瓦爾斯基·里昂
Next subject: Kowalski, Leon.
工程師，廢物處理
Engineer, waste disposal.
檔案區段：新僱員，6天
File section: New employee, six days.
進來
Come in.
呼叫韋伯先生，請到A區9扇區報道
Calling Mr. Webber...please report to Zone A Sector 9.
複製中心9層，有B1級安全警報
Replication Center Level 9, we have a B1 security alert.
請做好身份檢查準備
Stand by for ID check, please.
坐下
Sit down.
複製中心9層，有B1級安全警報
Replication Center Level 9, we have a B1 security alert.
請做好身份檢查準備
Stand by for ID check, please.
不介意我說話吧？
Care if I talk?
我接受測試時會有點緊張
I'm kind of nervous when I take tests.
請別動就好
Just please don't move.
哦，抱歉
Oh, sorry.
我今年已經做過智力測驗
I already had an IQ test this year.
我覺得沒做過這種...
I don't think I've had one of these.
反應時間是一個因素，所以要專心
Reaction time is a factor, so pay attention.
現在，盡可能快答
Now answer as quickly as you can.
好，行
Yeah, sure.
杭特華沙1187號
1187 at Hunterwasser.
- 是那家旅館　- 什麼？
That's the hotel.  -What?
- 我住的地方　- 好地方？
-Where I live.  -Nice place?
當然，應該是吧
Yeah, sure, I guess.
這是測試的一部份嗎？
Is that part of the test?
不，只是讓你熱身，就這樣
No. Just warming you up. That's all.
哦，那裏並不豪華什麼的
It's not fancy or anything.
你在一片沙漠裏，獨自行走在沙地上，突然間...
You're in a desert, walking along in the sand, when all of a su--
- 現在是測試了？　- 是的
Is this the test, now? -Yes.
你在一片沙漠裏，獨自行走在沙地上
You're in a desert, walking along in the sand...
- 突然間你往下看...　- 哪一個？
- ...when all of a sudden you look down--　-What one?
- 什麼？　- 哪一個沙漠？
-What?　-What desert?
是哪個沙漠並無分別，這完全是假設
Doesn't make any difference what desert it is.　It's completely hypothetical.
- 但是我怎麼會在那裏？　- 也許你吃飽撐的
-But how come I'd be there?　-Maybe you're fed up.
也許你想放飛自我，誰知道？
Maybe you wanna be by yourself.　Who knows?
你往下看，看見一隻烏龜，里昂
You look down and see a tortoise. Leon
- 它正向你爬過來...　- 烏龜？那是什麼？
-It's crawling towards you--　-Tortoise? What's that?
- 你知道海龜是什麼吧？　- 當然
-You know what a turtle is?　-Of course.
同樣的東西
Same thing.
我從沒見過海龜
I've never seen a turtle.
但我明白你的意思
But I understand what you mean.
你伸手下去，你把烏龜背朝下翻過來，里昂
You reach down, you flip the tortoise over on its back. Leon.
是你編造的這些問題嗎，霍爾登先生？
Do you make up these questions, Mr. Holden?
還是他們寫下來給你的？
Or do they write them down for you?
烏龜背朝下躺著，腹部在太陽下烤著
The tortoise lays on its back, its belly baking in the sun...
拍打四肢，想把自己翻過來，但辦不到...
...beating its legs, trying to turn itself over, but it can't...
除非有你幫忙，但是你沒幫忙
...not without your help. But you're not helping.
你什麼意思，我沒幫忙？
What do you mean I'm not helping?
我的意思是你沒幫忙
I mean, you're not helping.
為什麼會這樣，里昂？
Why is that, Leon?
這些只是問題，里昂
They're just questions, Leon.
回答你的詢問，是他們寫給我的
In answer to your query, they're written down for me.
這是個測試，設計來激發情緒反應
It's a test designed to provoke an emotional response.
我們可以繼續嗎？
Shall we continue?
用一個詞來描述
Describe in single words
只說你心裏想到的好處
only the good things that come into your mind...
關於你的母親
...about your mother.
我母親？
My mother?
是的
Yeah.
我來跟你說說我的母親吧
Let me tell you about my mother.
一段新生活就在地外殖民地等候你
A new life awaits you in the Off-world colonies.
重新開始的機會
The chance to begin again...
在那機會與冒險的黃金之地
...in a golden land of opportunity and adventure.
一段新生活就在地外殖民地等候你
A new life awaits you in the Off-world colonies.
重新開始的機會
The chance to begin again...
在那機會與冒險的黃金之地
...in a golden land of opportunity and adventure.
客戶訂做，遺傳工程，類人複製人
The custom-tailored, genetically, Engineered humanoid Replicant...
特為你的需求設計
...designed especially for your needs.
來吧，美國
So come on, America.
讓我們一起合作...
let's put our team up there...
給我四個
Give me four.
不，四個，二，二，四
No, four. Two, two. Four.
還有麵條
And noodles.
他說你被捕了，戴卡德先生
He say you under arrest, Mr. Deckard.
找錯人了，老兄
Got the wrong guy, pal.
他說你是銀翼殺手
He say you Blade Runner.
告訴他我在吃東西
Tell him I'm eating.
布萊恩特警監....
Captain Bryant...
布萊恩特，是嗎?
Bryant, huh?
黃色三號，爬升並維持高度4000
Yellow 3.  Climb and maintain 4000.
最後下降
Final descent.
現在在降落航道，標記航線
Now on glide path. Mark course.
越過著陸入口
Over the landing threshold.
- 嗨，戴克　- 布萊恩特
Hiya, Deck.  -Bryant.
如果我只是叫你，你不會來的
You wouldn't have come if I just asked you to.
坐下，夥計
Sit down, pal.
得了，別這麼混帳，戴卡德
Come on, don't be an asshole, Deckard.
有四個皮子貨在街上閒晃
I've got four skin-jobs walking the streets.
他們偷襲一艘地外世界穿梭船，殺了船員和乘客
They jumped a shuttle Off-world, killed the crew and passengers.
他們兩周前發現穿梭船在海岸飄流
They found the shuttle drifting off the coast two weeks ago...
所以我們知道他們在附近
...so we know they're around.
- 丟臉　- 不，先生，不丟臉
Embarrassing.  -No, sir, not embarrassing.
永遠不會有人發現他們在這裏
No one's ever gonna find out they're down here.
因為你要找到他們，把他們排除掉
Because you're gonna spot them and air them out.
我不在這裏上班了
I don't work here anymore.
交給霍爾登吧，他不錯
Give it to Holden. He's good.
我給了
I did.
他還可以呼吸，只要沒人拔他管子
He can breathe okay as long as nobody unplugs him.
他不夠好，沒你行
He's not good enough. Not good as you.
我需要你，戴克，這次很糟，最糟的
I need you, Deck. Now, this is a bad one, the worst yet.
我需要老的銀翼殺手
I need the old Blade Runner.
我需要你的魔力
I need your magic.
我進來之前就辭職了，布萊恩特
I was quit when I come in here, Bryant.
我現在更加要辭職
I'm twice as quit now.
原地站住！
Stop right where you are.
你知道實情的，夥計
You know the score, pal?
你要不是警察的話，就只是個小人物
If you're not cop, you're little people.
沒得選，嗯？
No choice, huh?
沒得選，夥計
No choice, pal.
我今年已經做過智力測驗
I already had an IQ test this year.
我覺得沒做過這種
I don 't think I've ever had one of these.
反應時間是一個因素，所以要專心
Reaction time is a factor, so please pay attention.
- 現在，盡可能快答　- 好，行
-Answer as quickly as you can.　-Yeah, sure.
杭特華沙1187號
1187 at Hunterwasser.
- 是那家旅館　- 什麼？
Yeah. That's the hotel.   -What?
- 我住的地方　- 好地方？
-Where I live.   -Nice place?
對，當然，應該是吧
Yeah, sure, I guess.
兩周前有人從地外殖民地逃走
There was an escape from the Off-world colonies two weeks ago.
六個複製人，三男三女
Six Replicants: three male, three female.
他們屠殺了23人，偷襲了一艘穿梭船
They slaughtered 23 people and jumped a shuttle.
空中巡邏隊在海岸發現了那艘船
An aerial patrol spotted the ship off the coast.
沒有船員，沒有他們的蹤跡
No crew, no sight of them.
三天前，夜裏他們想闖入泰瑞爾公司
Three nights ago they tried to break into Tyrell Corporation.
其中兩人穿過一個電場時給燒死
Two of them got fried running through an electrical field.
我們跟丟了其他人
We lost the others.
有可能，他們也許會試圖作為僱員潛入
On the possibility they might try to infiltrate as employees...
我叫霍爾登去對新工人做沃伊特-坎普測試
...I had Holden go over and run Voight-Kampff tests on the new workers.
看起來他找到了一個
Looks like he got himself one.
你往下看，看見一隻烏龜，對你爬過來
So you look down and you see a tortoise. It's crawling towards you.
那是里昂
That's Leon.
星際彈藥運輸者
Ammunition loader on intergalactic runs.
他能整日整夜扛著400磅原子負載
He can lift 400-pound atomic loads all day and night.
唯一能傷到他的辦法就是殺了他
The only way you can hurt him is to kill him.
我沒搞懂，他們冒險回地球來幹嘛？
I don't get it. What do they risk coming back to Earth for?
這不尋常，為什麼...
...That's unusual. Why...?
他們想從泰瑞爾公司得到什麼?
What do they want out of the Tyrell Corporation?
這得你告訴我，夥計，所以才找你來
Well, you tell me, pal. That's what you're here for.
- 這是什麼？　- Nexus 6 型
-What's this?　-Nexus 6.
羅伊·貝迪　啟動日期：2016年
Roy Batty.  Incept date: 2016.
戰鬥型號，最優自給
Combat model. Optimum self-sufficiency.
可能是帶頭的
Probably the leader.
這是佐拉
This is Zhora.
她被訓練成為地外世界的刺殺組
She's trained for an Off-world kick murder squad.
說到美女與野獸
Talk about Beauty and the Beast.
她兩者都是
She's both.
第四個皮子貨是普莉絲，基本娛樂型號
The fourth skin-job is Pris, a basic pleasure modeI.
外部殖民地軍人俱樂部的標準項目
The standard item for military clubs in the outer colonies.
他們的設計各方面都是複製人類，除了他們的感情
They were designed to copy human beings in every way except their emotions.
但設計者估算經過幾年...
The designers reckoned after a few years...
他們可能會發展出自己的情緒反應
...they might develop their own emotional responses.
仇恨、愛、恐懼、憤怒、羨慕
Oh, hate, love, fear, anger, envy.
所以他們造了失效保護裝置
So they built in a fail-safe device.
那是什麼呢？
Which is what?
四年的預期壽命
Four-year lifespan.
現在，泰瑞爾公司那邊有一個Nexus 6 型
Now, there's a Nexus 6 over at the Tyrell Corporation.
我要你過去用機器測測它
I want you to go put the machine on it.
要是機器不管用呢？
And if the machine doesn't work?
你喜歡我們的貓頭鷹嗎？
Do you like our owl?
它是人造的？
It's artificial?
它當然是
Of course it is.
一定很貴
Must be expensive.
非常貴，我是瑞秋
Very. I'm Rachael.
戴卡德
Deckard.
看起來你感覺我們的工作對大眾無益
It seems you feel our work is not a benefit to the public.
複製人像其它的機器一樣，要麼有益要麼有害
Replicants are like any other machine: They're either a benefit or a hazard.
如果它們有益，就不是我的問題了
If they're a benefit, it's not my problem.
我可以問你一個私人問題嗎？
May I ask you a personal question?
當然
Sure.
你曾經錯誤除役過一個人類嗎？
Have you ever retired a human by mistake?
沒有
No.
但是以你的位置，那是一個風險
But in your position, that is a risk.
這是一個移情測試嗎?
Is this to be an empathy test?
毛細血管擴張，俗稱臉紅？
Capillary dilation of the so-called blush response?
瞳孔的波動
Fluctuation of the pupil.
虹膜無意識擴大
Involuntary dilation of the iris.
我們簡稱它為沃伊特-坎普
We call it Voight-Kampff for short.
戴卡德先生，埃爾登·泰瑞爾博士
Mr. Deckard, Dr. Eldon Tyrell.
示範一下
Demonstrate it.
我要看看它的運作
I wanna see it work.
對像在哪？
Where's the subject?
我想看它用在一個人上
I wanna see it work on a person.
我要看看否定反饋，再給你提供一個肯定反饋
I wanna see a negative before I provide you with a positive.
那是要證明什麼？
What's that gonna prove?
滿足我一下
Indulge me.
在你身上？
On you?
試試她
Try her.
這裏太亮了
It's too bright in here.
你介意我抽煙嗎？
Do you mind if I smoke?
不會影響測試的
It won't affect the test.
好了，我會問你一連串的問題
AII right, I'm gonna ask you a series of questions.
只要放鬆，盡量簡單回答
Just relax and answer them as simply as you can.
你的生日
It's your birthday.
- 有人送給你一個小牛皮錢包　- 我不會接受
-Someone gives you a calfskin wallet.  -I wouldn't accept it.
同時，我會向警方舉報送給我的人
Also, I'd report the person who gave it to me to the police.
你有一個小男孩，他給你看他的蝴蝶標本
You've got a little boy.　He shows you his butterfly collection...
加上殺昆蟲的瓶子
...plus the killing jar.
我會帶他看醫生
I'd take him to the doctor.
你在看電視
You're watching television.
忽然發覺有一隻黃蜂爬在你手臂上
Suddenly you realize there's a wasp crawling on your arm.
我會殺了它
I'd kill it.
你在讀雜誌，你碰到一整頁女孩裸體照
You're reading a magazine. You come across a full-page nude photo of a girl.
這是在測試我是複製人還是女同嗎，戴卡德先生？
Is this testing whether I'm a Replicant or a lesbian, Mr. Deckard?
請直接回答問題
Just answer the questions, please.
你把它拿給丈夫看
You show it to your husband.
他很喜歡，把它掛在你們臥室牆上
He likes it so much he hangs it on your bedroom wall.
我不會讓他掛
I wouldn't let him.
- 為什麼？　- 他有我應該就夠了
Why not?  -I should be enough for him.
再問一題
One more question.
你在看一齣舞台劇，一場宴會正在進行
You're watching a stage play, a banquet is in progress.
賓客正享用生蠔開胃菜
The guests are enjoying an appetizer of raw oysters.
主菜包括燉狗肉
The entree consists of boiled dog.
你可否出去一會兒，瑞秋？
Would you step out for a few moments, Rachael?
謝謝
Thank you.
- 她是複製人，對吧？　- 我很佩服
She's a Replicant, isn't she?  -I'm impressed.
通常要問多少問題才會認出一個來？
How many questions does it usually take to spot one?
- 我沒明白，泰瑞爾　- 多少個問題？
-I don't get it, Tyrell.　-How many questions?
20到30個，互相對照
Twenty, thirty, cross-referenced.
對瑞秋來說超過100個了，不是嗎？
It took more than a hundred for Rachael, didn't it?
她不知道？
She doesn't know.
她開始懷疑了，我想
She's beginning to suspect, I think.
懷疑？它怎會不知道自己是什麼？
Suspect? How can it not know what it is?
在泰瑞爾這兒，商業是我們的目標
Commerce is our goal here at Tyrell.
「比人類更人類」是我們的座右銘
''More human than human'' is our motto.
瑞秋是一個實驗，如此而已
Rachael is an experiment, nothing more.
我們開始賞識他們
We began to recognize in them
一種奇怪的沉迷
a strange obsession.
畢竟他們缺乏情感經驗
After all, they are emotionally inexperienced
只有幾年的時間來存儲經驗
with only a few years in which to store up the experiences
這經驗卻是你我坦然接受的
which you and I take for granted.
如果我們賜予他們一段過去
If we gift them with a past,
我們就給他們創造了情感依靠和安慰
we create a cushion or a pillow for their emotions...
從而讓我們能更好地控制他們
...then consequently we can control them better.
記憶
Memories.
你說的是記憶
You're talking about memories.
反應時間是一個因素，所以請專心
Reaction time is a factor, so please pay attention.
- 現在，你回答的越快越好　- 好的
-Now answer as quickly as you can.　-Sure.
杭特華沙1187號
1187 at Hunterwasser.
- 是那家旅館　- 什麼？
-Yeah. That's the hotel.   -What?
- 我住的地方　- 地方不錯？
-Where I live.   -Nice place?
對，當然，應該吧　這是測試的一部份？
-Yeah, sure, I guess.     -Is that part of the test?
不是
No.
科瓦爾斯基
Kowalski.
時間
Time...
夠了
...enough.
你拿到你寶貴的照片了嗎？
Did you get your precious photos?
有人在那裏
Someone was there.
人？
Men?
警察？
Policemen?
天使火墜
Fiery the angels fell
悶雷陣陣滾過海濱
Deep thunder rolled around their shores
與Orc半人海獸之火同燃
Burning with the fires of Orc
你不能來這裏!
You not come here!
非法！
Illegal!
很冷的！那是我的眼睛！冷凍著!
Cold! Those are my eyes! Freezing!
是的
Yes.
問題
Questions.
形態，壽命，啟動日期
Morphology. Longevity. Incept dates.
不知道，我不知道這些東西
Don't know. I don't know such stuff.
我只做眼睛
I just do eyes.
只有眼睛，只是基因設計
Just eyes, just genetic design.
只有眼睛
Just eyes.
你是Nexus型？
You Nexus, huh?
我設計了你的眼睛
I design your eyes.
周
Chew...
但願你能看見我用你的眼睛所看見的
...if only you could see what I've seen with your eyes.
現在
Now...
問題
...questions.
我不知道答案
I don't know answers.
誰知道？
Who does?
泰瑞爾，他什麼都知道
Tyrell. He knows everything.
泰瑞爾公司？
Tyrell Corporation?
他是大老闆，大天才，他設計了你的心智
He big boss. Big genius.　He design your mind.
你的大腦
Your brain, huh?
聰明
Smart.
很冷
Very coId.
不是容易見的人...
Not an easy man to see...
給我外套
Give me coat.
...我猜想？
...I guess?
賽巴斯汀
Sebastian.
他帶你去那裏，他帶你去那裏
He take you there. He take you there.
哪個賽巴斯汀?
Sebastian who?
J... J.F.
J.F...
賽巴斯汀
...Sebast... .
那麼
Now...
在哪裏...我們可以找到...這位
...where......would we find this...
J. F. 賽巴斯汀？
...J.F. Sebastian?
我們繼續，可以嗎？
Let's continue, shall we?
用一個詞來描述
Describe in single words...
只說你心裏想到的好處
...only the good things that come into your mind
- 關於你母親　- 我母親？
about your mother.    -My mother?
是的
Yeah.
我來跟你說說我的母親
I'll tell you about my mother.
聲紋辨織，請說出你樓層號碼
Voice print identification. Your floor number, please.
- 戴卡德，97　- 97，謝謝，戴克
-Deckard, 97.　-97. Thank you. Danke.
我想見你
I wanted to see you.
所以我等著，讓我幫你
So I waited. Let me help you.
我為何需要幫忙？
What do I need help for?
我不知道他為何對你說出他所做的
I don't know why he told you what he did.
去跟他談
Talk to him.
他不會見我
He wouldn't see me.
想喝點嗎？
You want a drink?
不？
No?
你認為我是複製人，對吧？
You think I'm a Replicant, don't you?
瞧
Look.
是我和我母親一起
It's me with my mother.
是嗎？
Yeah?
記得你六歲的時候嗎？
Remember when you were 6?
你和你哥哥從地下室窗戶溜進一棟空大樓
You and your brother snuck into an empty building through a basement window.
你們要玩醫生遊戲？
You were gonna play doctor?
他給你看他的，而輪到你時，你害怕逃走了
He showed you his, and when it got to be your turn, you chickened and ran.
記得這事嗎？
Remember that?
這事你跟誰說過嗎？
Did you ever tell anybody that?
你母親，泰瑞爾，任何人？
Your mother, Tyrell, anybody, huh?
記得住在你窗外灌木叢的蜘蛛嗎？
You remember the spider that lived in the bush outside your window?
橙色身體，綠色的腿？
Orange body, green legs?
整個夏天看它織了一張網？
Watched her build a web all summer?
後來有一天，上面有個大卵
Then one day, there's a big egg in it.
卵孵化了
The egg hatched... .
- 卵孵化了...　- 然後呢
-The egg hatched...　-And?
...一百隻小蜘蛛爬出來
...and a hundred baby spiders came out.
它們吃了她
And they ate her.
植入
Implants.
那不是你的回憶，是別人的
Those aren't your memories, they're somebody else's.
是泰瑞爾侄女的
They're Tyrell's niece's.
好吧，糟糕的笑話
Okay. Bad joke.
我說了個糟糕的笑話　你不是複製人
I made a bad joke.  You're not a Replicant.
回家吧，好嗎？
Go home. Okay?
不，真的，我很抱歉
No, really. I'm sorry.
回家吧
Go home.
想喝一杯嗎?
Want a drink?
我給你倒點酒，我給你拿個杯子
I'll get you a drink.  I'll get a glass.
(字幕譯者：我實在看不清這些字)
你忘了你的袋子
You forgot your bag.
我迷路了
I'm lost.
別擔心，我不會傷害你的
Don't worry, I won't hurt you.
- 你叫什麼?　- 普莉絲
What's your name?  -Pris.
我叫 J.F. 賽巴斯汀
Mine's J.F. Sebastian.
- 嗨　- 嗨
-Hi.　-Hi.
你要去哪裏？
Oh, where were you going?
回家？
Home?
我沒有家
I don't have one.
我們嚇了對方一大跳，是吧？
We scared each other pretty good, didn't we?
確實是
We sure did.
我餓了，J.F.
I'm hungry, J.F.
我有食物在裏面
I got stuff inside.
你要進來嗎？
You wanna come in?
我正希望你說這話
I was hoping you'd say that.
你就一個人住在這樓裏？
Do you live in this building all by yourself?
對，目前我差不多就是一個人住在這裏
Yeah, I live here pretty much alone right now.
這附近不缺房子
No housing shortage around here.
每個人都有足夠的空間
Plenty of room for everybody.
小心水
Watch out for the water.
一定很寂寞，J.F.
Must get loneIy here, J.F.
不算是，我製造朋友
Not really. I make friends.
他們是玩具，我的朋友是玩具，我做了他們
They're toys. My friends are toys. I make them.
是一個愛好，我是基因設計師
It's a hobby. I'm a genetic designer.
你知道那是什麼嗎？
Do you know what that is?
不知道
No.
現在
Now.
喲呵，又回家了
Yoo-hoo, home again.
又回家了又回家了嘰嘰嘎嘎
Home again, home again, jiggidy-jig.
- 晚安，J.F.！　- 晚安，夥計們
-Good evening, J.F.　-Evening, fellas.
他們是我朋友，是我做的
They're my friends. I made them.
你的家人呢？
Where are your folks?
- 我算是個孤兒　- 喔
- I'm sort of an orphan. -Oh
那你的朋友呢？
What about your friends?
我有一些，不過我得找到他們
I have some, but I have to find them.
明天我會讓他們知道我在哪裏
I'II let them know where I am tomorrow.
哦?
Oh.
我可以幫你拿那些東西嗎？
Can I take those things for you?
濕透了，不是嗎?
They're soaked, aren't they?
增強224到176
Enhance 224 to 176.
增強，停
Enhance. Stop.
推入
Move in.
停
Stop.
拉出，右移，停
Pull out, track right.  Stop.
置中，拉回
Center and pull back.
停
Stop.
跟隨右45
Track 45 right.
停
Stop.
置中然後停
Center and stop.
增強34至36
Enhance 34 to 36.
右搖再拉回
Pan right and pull back.
停
Stop.
增強34至46
Enhance 34 to 46.
拉回
Pull back.
等等，向右
Wait a minute. Go right.
停
Stop.
增強57至19
Enhance 57-19.
跟隨左45
Track 45 left.
停
Stop.
增強15至23
Enhance 15 to 23.
就這裏給我一份複印
Give me a hard copy right there.
魚？
Fish?
我想這是由本地製造的
I think it was manufactured locally.
最高品質，上等工藝
Finest quality. Superior workmanship.
這裏有製作者的序號
There is the maker's serial number.
990-6947
XB-71
有意思
Interesting.
不是魚  蛇鱗
Not fish. Snake scale.
蛇
Snake.
找找阿布杜爾·本·哈桑，是他做的這條蛇
Try Abdul Ben Hassan. He make this snake!
阿布杜爾·哈桑？
Abdul Hassan?
我是警察，我想問你幾個問題
I'm a police officer. I'd like to ask you a few questions.
人造蛇執照XB-71，是你嗎？
Artificial snake license XB71, that's you?
這是你的作品吧？你賣給誰了？
This is your work, huh? Who did you sell it to?
我的作品？沒多少人付得起這樣的品質
My work? Not too many could afford such quality.
- 有多少？　- 很少
How many?  -Very few.
- 是多少？ - 瞧，朋友
-How few?  -Look, my friend--
塔菲·路易斯，在第四區，唐人街
Taffey Lewis'.  Down in Fourth Sector, Chinatown.
現在通行...現在通行...
Cross now. Cross now.
酒保
Bartender.
塔菲·路易斯？
Taffey Lewis?
謝謝
Thank you.
- 塔菲？  - 怎麼
-Taffey?　-Yeah?
- 我想問你幾個問題　- 放吧
I'd like to ask you a few questions.  -Blow.
你曾跟埃及人買過蛇嗎，塔菲？
You ever buy snakes from the Egyptian, Taffey?
經常買，老兄
AII the time, pal.
見過這女孩嗎？
You ever see this girl, huh?
沒見過，走開
Never seen her. Buzz off.
你的執照還有效嗎，老兄?
Your licenses in order, pal?
嘿，路易，這人口渴了
Hey, Louie. The man is dry.
給他一杯免費的，好嗎？ 再見
Give him one on the house, okay? See?
喂?
Hello?
以前是有人從我身邊走開過，但不是...
I've had people walk out on me before, but not when...
在我那麼迷人的時候
...I was being so charming.
我在一家酒吧，此時此刻，在第四區
I'm in a bar, here now, down in the Fourth Sector.
塔菲·路易斯在這裏
Taffey Lewis is on the line.
要不你過來這裏喝一杯？
Why don't you come on down here and have a drink?
我覺得不好，戴卡德先生
I don 't think so, Mr. Deckard.
那不是我去的地方
That's not my kind of place.
去別的地方？
Go someplace eIse?
女士們先生們
Ladies and gentlemen...
塔菲·路易斯獻上，莎樂美小姐與蛇
... Taffey Lewis presents Miss Salome and the snake.
看她與大蛇同歡
Watch her take the pleasure from the serpent...
這曾經敗壞過男人哦
... that once corrupted man.
打擾了，莎樂美小姐，我可以跟你談一下嗎?
Excuse me, Miss Salome, can I talk to you for a minute?
我是美國聯邦綜藝藝人協會的
I'm from the American Federation of Variety Artists.
是嗎？
Oh, yeah?
我不是來這裏讓你入會的
I'm not here to make you join.
不，女士，那不是我的部門
No, ma'am. That's not my department.
事實上
Actually...
我來自機密的道德凌虐委員會
...I'm from the Confidential Committee on Moral Abuses.
道德凌虐委員會？
Committee of Moral Abuses?
對，女士，有報告說這兒的管理層
Yes, ma'am. There's been some reports that the management...
曾經在這地方猥褻藝人
...has been taking liberties with the artists in this place.
這事我一無所知
I don't know nothing about it.
你有沒有感覺自己在任何方面被剝削？
Have you felt yourself to be exploited in any way?
你的「剝削」是什麼意思？
How do you mean ''exploited''?
比如為了得到這份工作...
Well, like to get this job.
我是說，你是否做過，或被要求做過任何...
I mean, did you do, or were you asked to do, anything that's...
下流或難堪的事
...lewd or unsavory or...
否則就排斥你
...otherwise repulsive to your person, huh?
- 你是當真的？　- 是的
-Are you for real?　-Oh, yeah.
我想...想檢查你的化妝室，可以的話
I'd like to check your dressing room, if I may.
- 查什麼？　- 查...查孔洞
-For what?　-For holes.
孔洞？
Holes?
你會驚訝於一個人可以通過它...
Well, you'd be surprised what a guy would go through to...
偷窺美麗的身體
...get a glimpse of a beautiful body.
不，我不會
No, I wouldn't.
嗯，小的...
Little...
...骯髒的孔洞，他們在牆上鑽孔
...dirty holes they drill in the wall
以觀看女士脫衣服
so they can watch a lady undress.
- 這是條真蛇嗎？　- 當然不是真的
-Is this a real snake?　-Of course it's not real.
你覺得我會在這種地方工作嗎，要是我買得起真蛇？
Think I'd be working in a place like this if I could afford a real snake?
那麼，要是有人真的想剝削我，我該找誰？
So if somebody does try to exploit me, who do I go to about it?
我
Me.
你是個敬業的人，給我擦乾
You're a dedicated man. Dry me.
現在通行...現在通行...
Cross now. Cross now.
行人止步... 行人止步...
Don 't walk. Don 't walk.
Don 't walk. Don 't walk. Don 't walk.
現在通行...現在通行...
Cross now. Cross now.
讓開! 別擋路!
Move! Get out of the way!
戴卡德
Deckard.
B-263-54.
B26354.
散開...散開
Move on. Move on.
等一下
A minute.
- 你要什麼？　- 青島
-Yeah, what do you want? -Tsingtao.
- 這夠嗎？　- 夠
-This enough? -Yeah.
布萊恩特
Bryant.
老天，戴卡德
Christ, Deckard
你看來和你扔在人行道上那個皮子貨差不多一樣糟
you look almost as bad as that skin-job you left on the sidewalk.
我要回家了
I'm going home.
可以跟他學學，蓋夫
Could learn from this guy, Gaff.
他根本就是單人屠宰場，他就是這樣
He's a goddamn one-man slaughterhouse, that's what he is.
還有四個要辦
Four more to go.
來，蓋夫，我們走
Come on, Gaff, let's go.
三個
Three.
- 還有三個要辦　- 是四個
-There's three to go.  -There's four.
那個皮子貨，你在泰瑞爾公司測試的
That skin-job you VK'd at the Tyrell Corporation...
瑞秋，消失了，無影無蹤
...Rachael, disappeared, vanished.
都不知道自己是個複製人
Didn't even know she was a Replicant.
跟大腦植入什麼的有關，泰瑞爾說的
Something to do with a brain implant, says Tyrell.
走吧，蓋夫
Come on, Gaff.
替我喝一點，老兄？
Drink some for me, huh, pal?
里昂
Leon.
我多大了？
How old am I?
我不知道
I don't know.
我的生日是2017年4月10日，我能活多久?
My birthday's April 10, 2017.　How long do I live?
四年
Four years.
比你多
More than you.
活在恐懼中很痛苦，不是嗎？
Painful to live in fear, isn't it?
沒什麼比有癢處但你永遠搔不到更糟了
Nothing is worse than having an itch you can never scratch.
我同意
I agree.
醒醒，是時候死了
Wake up. Time to die.
發抖？
Shakes?
我也是
Me too.
我抖得厲害
I get them bad.
是這行業的一部份
It's part of the business.
我不是做這行的
I'm not in the business.
我就是這行業
I am the business.
要是我往北走呢？
What if I go north?
消失
Disappear.
你會不會來追我？
Would you come after me?
獵殺我？
Hunt me?
不
No.
不，我不會
No, I wouldn't.
我欠你一次
I owe you one.
但有人會
But somebody would.
戴卡德
Deckard...
你知道我的那些檔案？
...you know those files on me?
啟動日期
The incept date.
壽命，那些事
The longevity. Those things.
你看過？
You saw them?
那些是...機密
They're......classified.
但你是個警察
But you're a policeman.
我……沒有看過
I......didn't look at them.
你知道，你那個沃伊特-坎普測試
You know, that Voight-Kampff test of yours...
你曾經測試過自己嗎?
...did you ever take that test yourself?
戴卡德？
Deckard.
我夢到音樂
I dreamt music.
我不知道自己會不會彈
I didn't know if I could play.
我記得上過課
I remember lessons.
我不知道那是我...還是泰瑞爾的侄女
I don't know if it's me or Tyrell's niece.
你彈得很美
You play beautifully.
現在，你吻我
Now you kiss me.
- 我不能依靠我的...　- 說，"吻我"
-I can't rely on my...     -Say, ''Kiss me. ''
吻我
Kiss me.
我要你
I want you.
再說
Again.
我要你
I want you.
擁抱我
Put your hands on me.
- 你做什麼？　- 對不起，看看而已
-What you doing?　-I'm sorry. Just peeking.
我看來如何？
How do I look?
你看來好點了
You look better.
- 只是好點？　- 你看來很漂亮
-Just better?　-Well......you look beautiful.
謝謝
Thanks.
你多大了？
How oId are you?
二十五
Twenty-five.
-你有什麼問題?　- 瑪士撒拉綜合癥
-What's your problem?　-Methuselah syndrome.
那是什麼?
What's that?
我的腺體，變老得太快
My glands, they grow old too fast.
這是你還留在地球的原因？
Is that why you're still on Earth?
對，我沒法通過體檢
Yeah. I couldn't pass the medical.
反正，我有點喜歡待在這裏
Anyway......I kind of like it here.
我喜歡你，就你這個樣子
I like you......just the way you are.
嗨，羅伊
Hi, Roy.
老天，你這兒的玩具真不錯
Hi. Gosh, you......really got some nice toys here.
這就是我對你說過的朋友
This is the friend I was telling you about.
這是我的救星，J.F.賽巴斯汀
This is my savior, J.F. Sebastian.
賽巴斯汀
Sebastian.
我喜歡留在原地的人
I like a man that stays put.
你完全一個人住在這裏，是嗎？
You live here all by yourself, do you?
是的
Yes.
來點早餐怎麼樣？
How about some breakfast?
我正要去做，失陪
I was just gonna make some. Excuse me.
怎樣？
Well?
- 里昂...　- 怎麼了?
-Leon...    -What's going on?
我...
I...
現在只有我們倆了
There's only two of us now.
我們太笨了，我們會死的
Then we're stupid and we'll die.
不，我們不會
No, we won't.
不，騎士吃掉皇后，看？
No. Knight takes queen, see?
我不會這樣下
Won't do.
你為何盯著我們看，賽巴斯汀？
Why are you staring at us, Sebastian?
因為...你們這麼不一樣
Because......you're so different.
你們是這麼的完美
You're so perfect.
是的
Yes.
你是哪一代的？
What generation are you?
Nexus 6型
Nexus 6.
啊，我就知道!
Ah, I knew it.
因為我為泰瑞爾公司做基因設計工作
Because I do genetic design work for the Tyrell Corporation.
你們有我的一部份
There's some of me in you.
給我展示一下
Show me something.
比如什麼？
Like what?
什麼都行
Like anything.
我們不是電腦，賽巴斯汀，我們有形有質
We're no computers, Sebastian. We're physical.
我思考，賽巴斯汀……故我在
I think, Sebastian......therefore, I am.
非常好，普莉絲，現在給他看看為什麼
Very good, Pris. Now show him why.
我們有許多共通點
We've got a lot in common.
你是什麼意思？
What do you mean?
相似的問題
Similar problems.
加速衰老
Accelerated decrepitude.
我對生化機械所知不多，羅伊，我希望我知道
I don't know much about bio-mechanics, Roy. I wish I did.
要是我們不盡快找人幫忙
If we don't find help soon...
普莉絲就活不久了
...Pris hasn't got long to live.
我們不能容許這樣
We can't allow that.
- 他厲害嗎？　- 誰？
-Is he good?　-Who?
- 你的對手　- 哦...泰瑞爾博士？
-Your opponent.　-Oh, Dr. Tyrell?
我下棋只擊敗過他一次，他是個天才
I've only beaten him once in chess. He's a genius.
他設計了你們
He designed you.
也許他能幫忙
Maybe he could help.
我很樂意向他提出
I'd be happy to mention it to him.
最好是我能親自和他談
Better if I talk to him in person.
不過我瞭解到，他是那類不易見到的人
But I understand he's a sort of hard man to get to.
是的，很難
Yes. Very.
你會幫我們嗎？
Will you help us?
我不能
I can't.
我們需要你，賽巴斯汀
We need you, Sebastian.
你是我們最好的也是唯一的朋友
You're our best and only friend.
我們很高興你找到我們
We're so happy you found us.
我認為世上沒有別的人類會幫助我們
I don't think there's another human being in the whole world who would've helped us.
六萬六千 普塞安科維奇
66,000 Prosser & Ankovich.
- 交易，交易價...    - 藍色入口
-Trade. Trade at two...   -Blue entry
J.F.賽巴斯汀先生
A Mr. J.F. Sebastian.
1-6-4-1-7.
16417.
在這個鐘點？
At this hour?
我能為你做什麼，賽巴斯汀？
What can I do for you, Sebastian?
皇后進主教六，將軍
Queen to bishop six. Check.
胡說
Nonsense.
等一下
Just a moment.
皇后進主教六？ 荒謬
Queen to bishop six, ridiculous.
皇后
Queen...
主教六
...bishop six.
騎士
Knight...
吃掉皇后
... takes queen.
你打什麼主意，賽巴斯汀？
What's on your mind, Sebastian?
你在想什麼？
What are you thinking about?
主教移到國王七，將死
Bishop to king seven. Checkmate.
主教移到國王七，將死，我認為
Bishop to king seven. Checkmate, I think.
頭腦風暴了，賽巴斯汀？
Got a brainstorm, huh, Sebastian?
牛奶和餅乾讓你睡不著?
Milk and cookies kept you awake, huh?
我們來討論一下
Let's discuss this.
你還是上來吧，賽巴斯汀
You better come up, Sebastian.
泰瑞爾先生？
Mr. Tyrell?
我...
I... .
我帶了個朋友
I brought a friend.
我很驚訝你沒有早點來
I'm surprised you didn't come here sooner.
要見你的製造者並不容易
It's not an easy thing to meet your maker.
他能為你做什麼呢？
And what can he do for you?
製造者能修補他的造物嗎？
Can the maker repair what he makes?
你想要...被修改嗎？
Would you like to be modified?
留在這裏
Stay here.
我想的是更根本一些的事
Had in mind something a little more radical.
什麼...
What...?
看起來是什麼問題？
What seems to be the problem?
死亡
Death.
恐怕這有點超出我的管轄範圍，你...
Well, I'm afraid that's a little out of my jurisdiction. You--
我想要更多的生命...
I want more life...
父親
father.
生命的實情
The facts of life.
要做出改變，在...
To make an alteration in the...
...有機生物系統進化上，是毀滅性的
...evolvement of an organic life system is fatal.
編碼序列一旦建立就不能修改
A coding sequence cannot be revised once it's been established.
為什麼不行?
Why not?
因為，在孕育的第二天
Because by the second day of incubation...
任何經歷逆轉突變的細胞...
...any cells that have undergone reversion mutations...
會導致回復體株遷移
...give rise to revertant colonies
就像老鼠離開下沉中的船
like rats leaving a sinking ship.
然後船...會沉沒
Then the ship sinks.
EMS甲基磺酸乙酯重組呢?
What about EMS recombination?
我們已經試過了
We've already tried it.
甲基磺酸乙酯是烷化劑
Ethyl methane sulfonate is an alkylating agent...
也是有效的誘變劑，它創造出一種...
and a potent mutagen. It created a
非常致命的病毒
virus so lethal the...
對像在離開實驗台前就死了
...subject was dead before he left the table.
那麼某種阻遏蛋白呢，能阻擋運作細胞
Then a repressor protein that blocks the operating cells.
不會阻礙複製，但它確實會導致一個複製錯誤
Wouldn't obstruct replication, but it does give rise to an error in replication.
因此...新形成的DNA串帶有一個變異
So that...the newly formed DNA strand carries a mutation...
你會再次得到病毒
...and you've got a virus again.
但這，所有這些，只是...
But this, all of this, is...
學術上的
...academic.
你是我們盡可能做到最好的
You were made as well as we could make you.
但不能持久
But not to last.
兩倍明亮一半持久的光芒
The light that burns twice as bright burns half as long.
而你已燃燒得非常非常明亮，羅伊
And you have burned so very, very brightly, Roy.
看看你
Look at you.
你是天之驕子
You're the prodigal son.
你是個了不得的獎勵
You're quite a prize.
我做過...可議之事
I've done......questionable things.
同樣也是非凡之事
Also extraordinary things.
縱情於你的時間吧
Revel in your time.
天堂裏沒什麼是生物機械之神不讓你做的
Nothing the god of biomechanics wouldn't let you in heaven for.
抱歉，賽巴斯汀
Sorry, Sebastian.
來吧，來吧
Come. Come.
經辨識，和泰瑞爾一起的屍體是25歲的白種男性
Body identified with Tyrell is a 25-year-old male Caucasian.
姓名：賽巴斯汀，J.F.賽巴斯汀
Name: Sebastian, J.F. Sebastian.
地址：布拉德伯利公寓大廈，第九區，N.F. 46751.
Address: Bradbury Apartments, Ninth Sector, NF4675 1.
我要你過去那裏...
I want you to go down there and--
本區地面交通封閉，你在這裏做什麼？
This sector's closed to ground traffic. What're you doing here?
我在工作，你在做什麼？
I'm working. What are you doing?
逮捕你，我正在做這事
Arresting you, that's what I'm doing.
我是戴卡德，銀翼殺手，26354
I'm Deckard, Blade Runner. 26354.
我已備案並接受監督
I'm filed and monitored.
等等，正在查
Hold on. Checking.
好，確認無誤，祝好運
Okay. Checked and cleared. Have a better one.
- 喂？　- 嗨！J.F.在嗎？
-Hello.　-Hi. Is J.F. there?
- 你是哪位？　- 艾迪，J.F.的老朋友
-Who is it?　-This is Eddie, old friend of J.F.'s.
這不是待友之道
That's no way to treat a friend.
（布拉德伯利）
又回家了又回家了.....
Home again, home again, jiggidy-jig.
晚安，J.F.
Good evening, J.F.
茶？
Tea?
加茶嗎？
More tea?
茶？
Tea?
加茶嗎？
More tea?
茶？
Tea?
加茶嗎？
More tea?
向手無寸鐵的對手開槍可不太公平
Not very sporting to fire on an unarmed opponent.
我以為你應該是好的
I thought you were supposed to be good.
你不是好人嗎？
Aren't you the good man?
來吧，戴卡德
Come on, Deckard.
讓我看看
Show me...
你是什麼做的
...what you're made of.
為自己驕傲嗎，小個子？
Proud of yourself, little man?
這是為了佐拉!
This is for Zhora.
這是為普莉絲
This is for Pris.
來吧，戴卡德
Come on, Deckard.
我就在這裏　但你得射直一點
I'm right here, but you've gotta shoot straight.
射直似乎還不夠好！
Straight doesn't seem to be good enough!
現在輪到我了
Now it's my turn.
我來之前會給你幾秒鐘時間
I'm gonna give you a few seconds before I come.
一...二...
One. Two.
三
Three.
四
Four.
普莉絲
Pris.
我來了!
I'm coming.
戴卡德!
Deckard!
四...五...
Four, five
怎樣活下來？
How to stay alive?
我能看見你
I can see you!
還不要!
Not yet!
不...
Not... .
對了
Yes.
你最好振作一點
You better get it up.
不然我要殺了你
Or I'm gonna have to kill you.
除非你活著，你就沒法玩了，如果你不玩...
Unless you're alive, you can't play.  And if you don't play... .
六，七!
Six, seven
下地獄或上天堂
Go to hell or go to heaven
很好! 就是這種精神!
Good, that's the spirit!
好痛
That hurt.
你那樣不理性
That was irrational of you.
更不用說...沒有運動精神
Not to mention......unsportsmanlike.
你要去哪？
Where are you going?
活在恐懼中的體驗還不錯，對吧？
Quite an experience to live in fear, isn't it?
這就是做奴隸的體會
That's what it is to be a slave.
我曾...見過你們人類不會相信之事
I've......seen things you people wouldn't believe.
戰艦在獵戶星座的肩旁燃燒
Attack ships on fire off the shoulder of Orion.
我觀看過C射線...
I watched C-beams...
...在唐懷瑟之門的黑暗裏閃耀
...glitter in the dark near the Tannhauser Gate.
...所有那些...瞬間都將消逝...
All those......moments will be lost...
...在時光裏...
...in time...
...如同...眼淚
...like......tears...
...消失在雨中
...in rain.
是時候...死了
Time to die.
你完成了人的工作，先生
You've done a man's job, sir.
我猜你不幹了，嗯？
I guess you're through, huh?
完成了
Finished.
真糟糕她不能活下去
It's too bad she won't live.
可話說回來，誰能呢？
But then again, who does?
瑞秋？
Rachael?
你愛我嗎？
Do you love me?
我愛你
I love you.
你信任我嗎？
Do you trust me?
我信任你
I trust you.
瑞秋？
Rachael?
真糟糕她不能活下去
It's too bad she won 't live.
可話說回來，誰能呢？
But then again, who does?
改編自菲利普·迪克小說《生化人會夢見電子羊嗎？》